<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>readxl on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/readxl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in readxl on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/readxl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Anomaly Detection Using R &amp; Tableau</title>
      <link>/2020/06/15/website-anomaly-detection-using-r-tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/15/website-anomaly-detection-using-r-tableau/</guid>
      <description>Written by: Ed Orlando, Data ScientistProject DescriptionAnomaly detection can be valuable in many ways. For example, anomalies can be used to detect fraud, better understand system health monitoring, or help data engineers identify spikes in website traffic. It can also be used to remove extreme outliers from datasets before modeling.
In this project, we identified webpage traffic outliers. The webpages analyzed are from the calendar year 2016 and focus on popular United States sports, entertainment, and political events and people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Employee Attrition Using R</title>
      <link>/2020/06/03/predicting-employee-attrition-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/03/predicting-employee-attrition-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Written by: Ed Orlando, Data ScientistProject DescriptionReducing turnover in an organization is vital. Using a fabricated data set, this project utilized advanced machine learning methods that accurately predicted which employees have a higher or lesser likelihood to leave. This project also displayed which key features influenced Employee Attrition at both the macro level as well as at the individual employee level.AcknowledgementI want to thank and give credit to Matt Dancho, CEO and Founder of Business Science University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Multiple Files from Various Folders Using R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoProblem StatementThis tutorial shows you how to load multiple files from multiple folders using R.
As a bonus, this article will also show you how to add the folder and file names to the final tibble.

Load LibrariesTidyverse and readxl are the only libraries required for this tutorial.
library(tidyverse)library(readxl)
Data DescriptionIn this example, Spotify playlist data was downloaded using Exportify.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>