<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Studio on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/r-studio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Studio on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Expected Values</title>
      <link>/2020/06/24/exploring-expected-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/24/exploring-expected-values/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed Orlando
IntroductionExpected values can be a little tricky to understand the first time around. Using some simple and more advanced examples, this article will help you understand the mystery behind Expected Values. We will specifically answer the following questions with the help of R:
Q1: How much do I gain - or lose - on average, if I repeatedly play a given gambling game?
Q2: How much can I expect to gain - or lose - by making a certain bet?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Power Calculations</title>
      <link>/2020/06/21/examining-power-calculations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/21/examining-power-calculations/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed Orlando
Introduction &amp;amp; Problem StatementCalculating sample sizes while accounting for power is fairly straight-forward if you have all the required inputs. Many universities have online calculators that help you determine the appropriate sample size. The variables needed to calculate the sample size while accounting for power are listed below. This article will utilize Cohen’s d calculations in the examples presented. If you are unfamiliar with any of the terms below, please click on any of the symbols for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Multiple Files from Various Folders</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoProblem StatementThis tutorial shows you how to load multiple files from multiple folders using R.
As a bonus, this article will also show you how to add the folder and file names to the final tibble.

Load LibrariesTidyverse and readxl are the only libraries required for this tutorial.
library(tidyverse)library(readxl)
Data DescriptionIn this example, Spotify playlist data was downloaded using Exportify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude and Motivation</title>
      <link>/2020/05/10/gratitude-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/10/gratitude-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed Orlando
First, I want to give a shout out to the team at White Lodging. Our team leader Adam Hutsler and Business Intelligence Manager Max Thomas are always coming up with creative ways to solve complex problems and create business value using Tableau and R. I also want to thank former Business Intelligence team members, Alex Williams and Troy Hill for their encouragement and advice throughout the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude and Motivation</title>
      <link>/2020/05/10/gratitude-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/10/gratitude-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoFirst, I want to give a shout out to the team at White Lodging. Our team leader Adam Hutsler and Business Intelligence Manager Max Thomas are always coming up with creative ways to solve complex problems and create business value using Tableau and R. I also want to thank former Business Intelligence team members, Alex Williams and Troy Hill for their encouragement and advice throughout the years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>